

Soheil Novinfard

Mobile Software Engineer (iOS Developer)

Personal Information

Location: United Kingdom, London

Contact Information

Phone: +44-7377178277 Email: novinfard@gmail.com

Website: www.novinfard.com GitHub: www.github.com/novinfard

Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/novinfard

Profile

I'm an iOS developer with 3+ years of expertise building mobile apps, working among a big team of talented developers to create some sports apps at Pulselive, a Sony company. Previous apps were written in Objective-C, since 2017 I'm also a Swift enthusiast.

My dream job would allow me to combine my technical skills with my passion for design in order to create high quality software with a great user experience. I would enjoy working in an environment where teamwork matters and I can be inspired by all people I work with. In a company ready for new challenges where you can always keep learning.

Academic Background

QUEEN MARY UNIVERSITY OF LONDON - 2017-2019

Master's degree, Software Engineering with Industrial Experience

SHARIF UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY – 2013-2015

Master's degree, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications

Main Skills

Mobile Applications, Objective-C, Swift, Backend Development, Web-socket, RESTful WebServices, CoreData, Realm

Other Skills

Project Management, Real-time applications, Web Applications, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, Codelgniter, Joomla!, XHTML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Scrum, Source Control, Git

Publications

M.R.Shahmoradi, S.Novinfard, "Developing a web service to automatic mapping web pages to mobile devices" 15th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2012), August 2012

Academic Awards

Organiser at 17th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2014), December 2014

Best Panel Chairman at 16th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering, September 2013



Work Experience

iOS Developer at Pulselive; London, United Kingdom

JULY 2018 - PRESENT

I have worked on some sports apps including ICC and BCCI and FFA. I mainly contributed in user interface and some back-end data handling subjects, plus radio(audio) player, video player, custom animations and deep link management.

My Personal Projects as iOS Developer; London, United Kingdom

JANUARY 2016 - PRESENT

Smart Wallet iOS Application January 2018 - present

This application assists for managing money. Different reports are presented in the application to help the user managing their money and budget. (written in Swift)

Transcription Helper iOS application September 2016 - present

The Transcribe Helper application is an assistant for people who want to work out a piece of audio, in order to write it out. (written in Objective-C)

iOS Developer at Ima Ravesh; Tehran, Iran

AUGUST 2014 - AUGUST 2017

Niniplus mobile application March 2014 - August 2017

Social network and real-time messaging for the community of pregnant women

Niniplus SMS web application August 2014 - March 2014

This application is an interactive SMS system which provides weekly messaging for pregnant women

Founder & Lead Web Application Developer at Egolt; Tehran, Iran

MARCH 2012 - JUNE 2017

Egolt Archive / Project / Voting / Like / Tooltip Joomla! extensions April 2013 - June 2017

Web Application Developer at Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting; Tehran, Iran

FEBRUARY 2009 - MARCH 2013

Negah Media web applicationSeptember 2009 - January 2011Kerman / Semnan / Hamadan IRIB websiteSeptember 2011 - May 2012

Languages

ENGLISH PROFESSIONAL WORKING PROFICIENCY

IELTS Academic Module Certificate with band score 7.0 (20th April 2017)

PERSIAN NATIVE

Interests and hobbies

Watching movies, Playing piano, Reading tech articles, Fitness